RG 178:002, Long Lane School
Connecticut State Library
- Series 4. Student Records, 1870-1973; 2003-028
  - Record of school year [grades], 1900-1956, undated
    - 1904-1905, 1905-1906, 2 volumes (Box 77)
    - 1906-1907, 1907-1908, 2 volumes (Box 78)
    - 1908-1909, 1909-1910, 2 volumes (Box 79)
    - 1910-1911, 1911-1912, 2 volumes (Box 80)
    - 1912-1913, 1913-1914, 2 volumes (Box 81)
    - 1913-1914, 1914-1915, 2 volumes (Box 82)
    - 1914-1915, 1915-1916, 2 volumes (Box 83)
    - 1916-1917, 1917-1918, 2 volumes (Box 84)
    - 1918-1919, 1919-1920, 2 volumes (Box 85)
    - 1920-1921, 1921-1922, 2 volumes (Box 86)
    - 1924-1925, 1925-1926, 2 volumes (Box 87)
    - 1926-1927, 1927-1928, 2 volumes (Box 88)
    - 1928-1929, 1929-1930, 2 volumes (Box 89)
    - 1930-1931, 1931-1932, 2 volumes (Box 90)
    - 1932-1933, 1933-1934, 2 volumes (Box 91)
    - 1934-1935, 1935-1936, 2 volumes (Box 92)
    - 1936-1937, 1937-1938, 2 volumes (Box 93)
    - 1938-1939, 1939-1940, 1940-1941, 3 volumes (Box 94)
    - 1941-1942, 1942-1943, 1943-1944, 3 volumes (Box 95)
    - 1944-1945, 1945-1946, 1946-1947, 1947-1948, 4 volumes (Box 96)
    - 1948-1949, 1949-1950, 1950-1951, 1951-1952, 4 volumes (Box 97)
    - 1952-1953, 1953-1956, undated, 3 volumes (Box 98)
  - Population statistics, 1916-1958
    - 1916-1922 (Box 113, Folder 6)
    - 1923-1935 (Box 113, Folder 7)
    - 1939-1942 (Box 113, Folder 8)
    - 1936-1938 (Box 113, Folder 9)
    - 1943-1946 (Box 113, Folder 10)
    - 1947-1950 (Box 113, Folder 11)
    - 1951-1954 (Box 113, Folder 12)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Population notebook, 1919-1929, 1939-1956, 1966-1968 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Student status and assignment, 1967-1968, undated (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Student identification numbers, 1917 April-1920 Nov (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Record summary cards, 1901-1916
    Arranged by identification number
    - 1396-2177 (Box 115)
  - Case files, circa 1910-1961
    - circa 1910-1920, 2003-028
      - 1725-2061 (Box 116)
      - 2062-2091 (Box 117)
    - 1928-1961, 2003-044
      - 3213-3230 (Box 1)
      - 3231-3253 (Box 2)
      - 3254-3291 (Box 3)
      - 3292-3311 (Box 4)
      - 3312-3333 (Box 5)
      - 3334-3352 (Box 6)
      - 3353-3370 (Box 7)
      - 3371-3392 (Box 8)
      - 3393-3421 (Box 9)
      - 3399-3417 (Box 10)
      - 3418-3449 (Box 11)
      - 3450-3468 (Box 12)
      - 3469-3485 (Box 13)
      - 3486-3502 (Box 14)
      - 3503-3523v (Box 15)
      - 3524-3541 (Box 16)
      - 3542-3557 (Box 17)
      - 3558-3575 (Box 18)
      - 3576-3594 (Box 19)
      - 3595-3613 (Box 20)
      - 3614-3631 (Box 21)
      - 3632-3651 (Box 22)
      - 3652-3667 (Box 23)
      - 3668-3686 (Box 24)
      - 3687-3703 (Box 25)
      - 3704-3720 (Box 26)
      - 3721-3739 (Box 27)
      - 3740-3757 (Box 28)
      - 3758-3775 (Box 29)
      - 3776-3790 (Box 30)
      - 3794-3809 (Box 31)
      - 3810-3826 (Box 32)
      - 3827-3837 (Box 33)
      - 3838-3852 (Box 34)
      - 3853-3868 (Box 35)
      - 3869-3885 (Box 36)
      - 3886-3902 (Box 37)
      - 3903-3918 (Box 38)
      - 3919-3932 (Box 39)
      - 3933-3947 (Box 40)
      - 3948-3964 (Box 41)
      - 3965-3980 (Box 42)
      - 3981-3995 (Box 43)
      - 3996-4012 (Box 44)
      - 4013-4024 (Box 45)
      - 4025-4040 (Box 46)
      - 4041-4060 (Box 47)
      - 4061-4076 (Box 48)
      - 4077-4090 (Box 49)
      - 4091-4105 (Box 50)
      - 4106-4116 (Box 51)
      - 4117-4137 (Box 52)
      - 4138-4157 (Box 53)
      - 4158-4174 (Box 54)
      - 4175-4191(#1) (Box 55)
      - 4191(#2)-4202 (Box 56)
      - 4203-4214 (Box 57)
      - 4215-4229 (Box 58)
      - 4230-4243 (Box 59)
      - 4244-4261 (Box 60)
      - 4262-4277 (Box 61)
      - 4278-4292 (Box 62)
      - 4293-4306 (Box 63)
      - 4307-4319 (Box 64)
      - 4320-4329 (Box 65)
      - 4330-4343 (Box 66)
      - 4344-4358 (Box 67)
      - 4359-4372 (Box 68)
      - 4373-4390 (Box 69)
      - 4391-4399 (Box 70)
      - 4400-4410 (Box 71)
      - 4411-4421 (Box 72)
      - 4422-4436 (Box 73)
      - 4437-4448 (Box 74)
      - 4449-4460 (Box 75)
      - 4461-4473 (Box 76)
      - 4474-4481 (Box 77)
      - 4482-4492 (Box 78)
      - 4493-4504 (Box 79)
      - 4505-4514 (Box 80)
      - 4515-4527 (Box 81)
      - 4528-4538 (Box 82)
      - 4539-4549 (Box 83)
      - 4550-4561 (Box 84)
      - 4562-4577 (Box 85)
      - 4578-4588 (Box 86)
      - 4589-4601 (Box 87)
      - 4602-4611 (Box 88)
      - 4612-4624 (Box 89)
      - 4625-4633 (Box 90)
      - 4634-4642 (Box 91)
      - 4643-4654 (Box 92)
      - 4655-4665 (Box 93)
      - 4666-4677 (Box 94)
      - 4678-4687 (Box 95)
      - 4688-4696 (Box 96)
      - 4697-4707 (Box 97)
      - 4708-4720 (Box 98)
      - 4721-4732 (Box 99)
      - 4733-4742 (Box 100)
      - 4743-4755 (Box 101)
      - 4756-4767 (Box 102)
      - 4768-4777 (Box 103)
      - 4778-4788 (Box 104)
      - 4789-4801 (Box 105)
      - 4802-4810 (Box 106)
- Series 5. School Records, 1874-1969; 2003-028
  - School journal, 1874-1877; 1 volume (Box 99)
  - Mailing list index, lawyers index, Index cards (Box 100)
  - Visitor sign-in book, 1917 January 18-1969 January 28; 4 volumes (Box 118)
  - Visiting agents book, 1878 April 20-1879 May 22; 1 volume (Box 119, Folder 1)
- Series 6. Reports, 1867-1990; 2003-028
  - Annual report, 1867-1942
    - 1872-1876 (Box 119, Folder 2)
    - 1878-1881 (Box 120, Folder 1)
    - 1882-1887 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - 1889-1897 (Box 120, Folder 3)
    - 1899-1904 (Box 120, Folder 4)
    - 1906-1910 (Box 120, Folder 5)
    - 1912-1916 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - 1918 (Box 120, Folder 7)
    - 1920-1938 (Box 120, Folder 8)
    - 1867-1878, 1 volume (Box 121, Folder 1)
    - 1879-1887, 1 volume (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - 1888-1902, 1 volume (Box 121, Folder 3)
    - 1932-1942 (Box 122, Folder 1)
  - Connecticut Digest of Administrative Reports to the Governor, 1947-1968 (Box 122)
    - 1947-1967 (Box 122, Folder 2)
    - 1968 (Box 122, Folder 3)
  - Annual objective and facility plan, 1986-1990 (Box 122)
    - 1986 (Box 122, Folder 4)
    - 1987 (Box 122, Folder 5-6)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 122, Folder 7)
    - 1990 (Box 122, Folder 8)
  - Walter G. Cady School annual report, 1987 (Box 122, Folder 9)
  - Investigation report, 1920 (Box 122, Folder 10)
  - Development proposal, 1945 October 4 (Box 122, Folder 11)
  - Study Committee to Governor Ribicoff, 1957 (Box 122, Folder 12)
- Series 7. Correspondence, 1884-1972; 2003-028
  - 1884 August 9-1925 December 5 (Box 123, Folder 1)
  - 1926 May 10-1929 December 4 (Box 123, Folder 2)
  - 1930 January 15-1972 June 19 (Box 123, Folder 3)
- Series 8. Financial Records, 1898-1963; 2003-028
  - Financial records, 1898-1960; 12 volumes (Box 101-112)
  - Budgets, 1929-1957
    - 1929-1931 (Box 123, Folder 4)
    - 1931-1933 (Box 123, Folder 5)
    - 1933-1935, 1947-1949 (Box 123, Folder 6)
    - 1949-1953 (Box 123, Folder 7)
    - 1955-1957 (Box 123, Folder 8)
  - Bank books, 1933 April -1934 January, 1946 January-May (Box 123, Folder 9)
  - Auditor's report, 1946-1963 (Box 123)
    - 1946-1947, 1959-1957 (Box 123, Folder 10)
    - 1958-1963 (Box 123, Folder 11)
  - Treasurer's report, 1928 July 10 (Box 123, Folder 12)
- Series 9. Policies, 1948-1990; 2003-028
  - Policies, 1948 December 4-1973 January 3, undated (Box 124, Folder 1)
  - Rules notebook, 1961-1963, undated (Box 124, Folder 2)
  - Manuals, 1950-1990, undated (Box 124)
    - 1950, 1968 (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - 1974, 1976 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - 1981 (Box 124, Folder 5)
    - 1985 (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - 1990 (Box 124, Folder 7-8)
    - undated (Box 124, Folder 9)
- Series 10. Staff Materials, 1948-1990; 2003-028
  - Directory, 1970, undated (Box 124, Folder 10)
  - Schedules, 1960, undated (Box 124, Folder 11)
  - Day book/Daily notes notebook, 1961-1968
    - 1961 August 8-1962 September 4, 1967 October 16-1968 April 1 (Box 125, Folder 1)
    - 1968 April 2-October 4 (Box 125, Folder 2)
  - Staff Council notebook, 1959 January 27-1960 March 1, 1968 August 6-October 1 (Box 125, Folder 3)
  - Housemother Council notebook, 1960 March 15-1961 January 3 (Box 125, Folder 4)
  - Physician's notebook on staff accidents, 1964 July 30-1971 September 8 (Box 125, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous notebooks, 1961 March-1968 October 1 (Box 125, Folder 6)
  - Memorandums, 1948 January 12-1972 June 15 (Box 125, Folder 7)
  - Forms, 1966-1968 (Box 125, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1963-1990, undated (Box 125, Folder 9)
- Series 11. Student Life, 1914-1982; 2003-028
  - Girl's Council notebook, 1958-1968
    - 1958 December 15-1959 October 21, 1960 November 10-1961 October 30 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - 1968 February 13-October 1 (Box 126, Folder 2)
    - 1968, undated (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Hygiene notebook, 1960-1968 (Box 126)
    - 1960-1968 (Box 126, Folder 4)
    - 1968 (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - Wages and expenses, 1914 August-1917 March 29 (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - Publications, 1953-1982 (Box 126)
    - 1953-1962 (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - 1963-1982 (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - 1982, undated (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Club activities, 1926 January 1-1929 July 23 (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Events, 1954-1970 (Box 127)
    - Graduation (Box 127)
      - 1954-1961 (Box 127, Folder 4)
      - 1962-1970 (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - Student productions
      - 1955-1961 (Box 127, Folder 6)
      - 1962-1970 (Box 127, Folder 7)
- Series 12. Publications, 1885-1984; 2003-028
  - Long Lane, 1885-1991
    - 1885-1991 (Box 127, Folder 8)
    - undated (Box 127, Folder 9-10)
  - Not produced by Long Lane, 1915-1984
    - 1915-1924 (Box 128, Folder 1)
    - 1927-1936 (Box 128, Folder 2)
    - 1939-1947 (Box 128, Folder 3)
    - 1948-1955 (Box 128, Folder 4)
    - 1956 (Box 128, Folder 5-7)
    - 1958 (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - 1967-1984, undated (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - undated (Box 129, Folder 3-6)
- Series 13. Committees and Conferences, 1932-1989; 2003-028
  - Conference of Superintendents of Correctional Institutions for Girls and Women, 1932-1953
    - Newspaper clippings, 1932 February 11-1951 November 18 (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1934 October 23-1953 November 19 (Box 129)
      - 1934 October 23-1950 March 27 (Box 129, Folder 8)
      - 1951 October 29-1953 November 19, undated (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - Conference Proceedings, 1932-1953
      - 1932-1936 (Box 129, Folder 10)
      - 1947 (Box 129, Folder 11)
      - 1948-1949 (Box 129, Folder 12)
      - 1950-1951 (Box 129, Folder 1)
      - 1952 (Box 130, Folder 2)
      - 1953 (Box 130, Folder 3)
      - undated (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - Committee of Fourteen, 1945-1966 (Box 130)
    - Minutes, 1945 March 20-1966 March 16 (Box 130)
      - 1945 March 20-1956 January 30 (Box 130, Folder 5)
      - 1955 November 30-1959 January 21 (Box 130, Folder 6)
      - 1959 March 18-1966 March 16 (Box 130, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1955 September 14-1966 November 6 (Box 130)
      - 1955 September 14-1961 April 6 (Box 130, Folder 8)
      - 1961 October 5-1962 November 27 (Box 130, Folder 9)
      - 1963 January 2-1966 November 6 (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - Commission on Accreditation for Corrections, 1975-1989 (Box 130)
    - Correspondence, 1983 April 1-1985 July 1 (Box 130, Folder 11)
    - Commission policy memo, 1984 February-1986 May (Box 130, Folder 12)
    - Newsletter, 1984 July-1989 June (Box 131, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1975 August-1987 February, undated (Box 131, Folder 2)
- Series 14. Inventories, 1918-1968; 2003-028
  - Room inventory, 1968 October 6-8 (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - Statement of resources, 1918 (Box 131, Folder 4)
  - Campus Keys notebook, undated (Box 131, Folder 5)
- Series 15. Newspaper Clippings, 1881-1998; 2003-028
  - 1881 November 19-1972 May 9 (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - 1957 February 1-1998 June 15 (Box 131, Folder 7)
- Series 16. Maps, undated; 2003-028
  - undated (Box 131, Folder 8)
- Series 17. Postcards, undated; 2003-028
  - Girls dressed up as butterflies (Box 132)
  - Girls dressed up as money (Box 132)
  - Living room of new home (Box 132)
  - Dining room of new house (Box 132)
  - Three girls in playroom (Box 132)
  - Allyn Home (Box 132)
  - Browning Staff House (Box 132)
  - William G. Cady School and Auditorium (Box 132)
  - Craig Home (Box 132)
  - Entrance Gate (Box 132)
  - Fairbank Recreation Building (Box 132)
  - Kimball Infirmary (Box 132)
  - Russell Home (Box 132)
  - Smith Home (Box 132)
  - Street Home (Box 132)
  - Superintendent's Residence (Box 132)
  - William G. Wilcox Administration Building (Box 132)
- Series 18. Scrapbooks, circa 1973-1980; 2003-028
  - (Box Item 132a)
- Series 19. Miscellaneous, 1926-1990; 2003-028
  - 1926-1990 (Box 131, Folder 9)
- Series 20. Photographs, circa 1880-2000; 2003-028
  - Events and activities, circa 1900-1999
    - circa 1900-1999, 124 photographs (Box 133)
    - circa 1990-1999, 164 photographs (Box 134)
    - circa 1910-1999, 45 photographs (Box 135)
  - Buildings, circa 1880-1995
    - circa 1880-1990, 64 photographs (Box 136)
    - circa 1917-1995, 71 photographs (Box 137)
    - circa 1894-1960, 33 photographs (Box 138)
  - Pageants, circa 1910-1920
    - circa 1910-1920, 45 photographs (Box 139)
    - circa 1910-1920, 50 photographs (Box 140)
  - Farm, circa 1890-1979; 52 photographs (Box 141)
  - Portraits, circa 1910-1957; 80 photographs (Box 142)
  - Outdoor views, circa 1950-1990; 112 photographs (Box 143)
  - Middletown flood, 1927 November 6; 8 photographs (Box 144)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1910-2000; 73 photographs (Box 144)
  - Oversize, circa 1870-1950
    - circa 1880-1950, 12 photographs (Box 145)
    - undated, 3 photographs (Box 146)
    - circa 1870-1920, 16 photographs (Box 147)
  - Photo albums, circa 1920-1930, circa 1978-1988; 2 albums (Box 148)
- Series 21. Works of Art, 1939-1950; 2003-028; Oversize
  - WPA paintings, 1939, undated
    - White and Gold, Edith Dale Manson, undated; oil
    - House at the Junction, S. DeMaio, 1939; oil
    - Muddy River, Thomas Guidone, 1939; oil
    - Plowing, Ernest M. Albert, undated; oil
    - Fish Market, Beatrice Cuming, undated; watercolor
    - A Bit of the Sea, Leslie Benson, undated; watercolor
    - Marina, Ralston Keeler, 1939; watercolor
    - Boats on an ocean, undated; watercolor
    - Path through a hilly area, undated; oil
  - Other paintings, 1950, undated
    - Proposed School Building for Long Lane Farm, Tower and Sellers Associates Architects, Middletown, CT, undated; chalk
    - Proposed Development Plot Plan, Tower and Sellers Associates Architects, Middletown, CT, undated; ink
    - Cape Cod, Al Malmgren, 1950; oil
    - Boats at a dock, Ted Kautz, undated; oil
    - Clock and teapot, Lephe Holden, undated; watercolor
    - Forest, undated; print
    - Ocean coast, undated; watercolor 3 items; located in box
- Series 22. Artifacts, 1926-1998; 2003-028
  - Film reels, 1936-1945, undated; 11 items (Box 149)
    - Gaspi, 1936 (Box 149)
    - New Mexico # 1 Indian Ceremonial Gallup, 1936 (Box 149)
    - New Mexico #2 Fiesta at Santa Fe, 1936 (Box 149)
    - Coronation of King and Queen, 1937 May (Box 149)
    - Gardening-Picnic Fair Long Lane, 1938 (Box 149)
    - California, 1945 October (Box 149)
    - Rosewall, undated (Box 149)
    - Old Mexico, undated (Box 149)
    - Bull Fight in Old Mexico, undated (Box 149)
    - Farm and plays (in color), undated (Box 149)
    - Is anybody listening?, National Audiovisual Center, undated (Box 149)
  - Film reels, video and audio tapes, 1936-1998, undated; 13 film reels, 2 video tapes, 1 audio tape (Box 150)
    - Labrador, 1936 (Box 150)
    - Visit of King and Queen, 1939 (Box 150)
    - Southern Trip, C.DeF.P. and E.A.H., 1941 (Box 150)
    - Trip no. 1, 1947 (Box 150)
    - Trip no. 2, 1947 (Box 150)
    - Royal wedding, undated (Box 150)
    - New Girl=Flower Gardens (color), undated (Box 150)
    - Washington, Williamsburg, Dogwood at Valley Forge, Claymont Del., Dickeyville Md,, Skyline Drive, Gettysburg Pa., Mr. and Mrs. Wilcox, undated (Box 150)
    - unlabeled film reels, undated; 6 items (Box 150)
    - Raymond Hilton Auditorium Dedication, 1995 September 22 (Box 150)
    - Long Lane Raid J.L., 1998 March 2 (Box 150)
    - Long Lane School Choir audio tape, undated (Box 150)
  - Straight jackets, undated; 2 items (Box 151)
  - Certificates, 1967-1994; 4 items (Box 152)
    - Silver plate made by DCYS Summer Project, 1967 (Box 152)
    - DCYS Certificate of Appreciation Superintendent Emeritus of Long Lane School, 1989 September 20 (Box 152)
    - "Outstanding Participation of the 1994 Connecticut State Employees' Campaign for Charitable Giving" Employees of Long Lane School, undated (Box 152)
    - DCYS Code of Conduct, undated (Box 152)
  - Trophies, 1926-1953, undated; 5 items (Box 153)
    - Sweepstakes Flower Department, Durham Fair, 1926 (Box 153)
    - Football Trophy, 1930-1939 (Box 153)
    - Deaconess Virginia C. Young Cup, 1935-1951 (Box 153)
    - Hit Pin Baseball, 1943-1953 (Box 153)
    - Policewoman's Association of Connecticut, undated (Box 153)
  - Ceramics, undated; 5 items (Box 154)
  - Xylophones, undated; 3 items (Box 155)
  - Chalkboards, undated; 15 items (Box 156)
  - Cash boxes, 1990; 3 items (Box 157)
  - Dictionaries, 1990; 2 items (Box 157)
  - Miscellaneous artifacts, undated (Box 158)
    - Box with war ration stamps, undated (Box 158)
    - Cooking and eating utensils, undated (Box 158)
    - Quote by Elbert Hubbard, undated (Box 158)
  - School Choir recordings, undated; 18 copies (Box 159)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1967-1991; 2 items (Box 160)
    - DCYS Child Care Worker of the Year Long Lane School, 1987-1991 (Box 160)
    - State of Connecticut General Assembly Resolution Saluting Long Lane School, 1967 April 25 (Box 160)
  - Stanford-Binet IQ Test, undated (Box 161)
  - Sewing chest, undated; Oversize
  - Cobbler's bench, undated; Oversize
  - Restraint chair, undated; Oversize